Contact

992818439 (Mobile) rocky198811@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kuldeepsingh1988 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

OOP

PHP

MySQL

Languages

Punjabi

English

Hindi

Certifications

Certified MVC Architect

Test Driven Development (TDD), PHPUnit Testing Course

Docker Mastery Training Course
Web Programming and Designing

Honors-Awards

NCC

National Football NCC (National Cadet Corps).

Employee Of The Month

Employee Of The Month

Employee Of The Month

Kuldeep Singh

Senior PHP Programmer, Technical Team Lead PHP-DevOps, Architectural Planning, SRE, MYSQL & MSSQL Database Expert Dehradun, Uttarakhand, India

Summary

I am...

I'm a PHP backend developer with a passion for building meaningful web applications and have more than 9 years of experience mostly in b2b, b2c, microservices, and third-party API's integration.

I'm highly experienced to deliver websites / web-applications from scratch with the software development life cycle (SDLC) process.

My strongest skills and how I learned them...

I'm very strong with OOPs (PHP), Relational Database Setup (MYSQL, MSSQL), Project Road Map Planning (Agile Methodology), team management, task distribution, and issue debugging.

I gained a lot of experience in recent years on many b2c websites to implement and lead all major aspects like PWA, GDPR, ADA, Cyber-Security, SEO, etc.

What I am looking for...

I'm looking for a backend developer/ full-stack developer/ technical lead position with a focus on the backend. I'm open to trying and learn new technologies but I'm highly experienced in PHP7 and RDS. I would love to share my knowledge, potentially in a technical leadership role.

One fact (outside of work) about me...

I really like to learn & implement upgraded versions of technologies which can help to improve the QA and time-line of any product. On the other hand, I keep myself up to date with the latest web technologies such as PHP, MYSQL, Artificial Intelligence, Motion UI, Cyber-Security, BlockChain technology, Docker, etc.

Additional information....

PHP Engineer

Relational Database Expert

Continues Integration

DevOps (GIT, Jenkins, Phing, Docker, Kubernetes)

Relational Database Expert

Challenging task taker.

Large team handling (15+ team members)

Delivered 70+ online applications.

Note: To get the experience in every technology is not possible but to learn them to prepare yourself for the next challenge is possible and I do that in my daily routine to learn something new every day.

Experience

BAMKO

Team Lead PHP DevOps June 2016 - Present (3 years 11 months)

Dehra Dun Area, India

Daily programming with technical issues debugging and team-leading were my major roles.

To do 40% programming and 60% team handing are my daily tasks.

Daily stand-up meetings to keep the team synchronized with each other.

Daily code review to maintain the quality of applications.

Implemented Agile Methodology to delivery quality and on-time delivery with ASANA tasks management tool.

Daily interaction with clients via skype and email to accomplish the work.

Ensuring that development standards, policies and procedures are adhered to.

Driving change for the implementation of efficient and effective strategies as advised by management.

Ensuring that all software developed within the team satisfies the business requirements as specified.

Delivered TWITTER & RIOT GAMES b2b websites for their merchants.

Delivered a Restful API for the INSTCART grocery delivery service.

Delivered a customized CMS to create and handle b2b / b2c stores.

Successfully delivered 50+ b2b stores and b2c stores.

Developed my own custom MVC architect framework and successfully delivered a b2c website with that.

Delivered highly optimized web applications.

Handled the team of 14+ professionals including PHP programmers,
Designers, DBA, SEO professionals, Content writers, Testers, Co-Ordinator,
DevOps Engineers and SYSTEM administrators.

Proactively involved in code deployments for DEV, QA, and production.

Lead the team to implement and understand the GIT (Enterprise In-House) version control system with Jenkins & Phing.

Delivered many projects by using PHP7, SOLID Principles, Test Driven Development, MYSQL (RDS), MS-SQL (RDS), Laravel, Codeigniter, Jquery, Angular Js, Ajax, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Jenkins, Phing, Docker, Kubernetes, CI/CD, PWA (Progressive Web Apps).

Integrated many third party web services and APIs like SAGE, SAP, UPS, Google, Facebook, Twitter, Single Sign-On, Oracle Punchout/Checkout, etc.

Arora Comfortechs Pvt. Ltd.
Senior Programmer Team Lead PHP
October 2014 - June 2016 (1 year 9 months)

Yamunanagar Area, India

Daily programming with technical / team leading was my major role.

To do 40% programming and 60% team handing were my daily tasks.

Daily stand-up meetings to keep the team synchronized with each other.

Daily code review to maintain the quality of code.

Implemented Agile Methodology to delivery quality and on-time delivery.

Daily call with clients from the US to gather new requirements and on-going work updates.

Weekly training to keep update the team with new technologies & good coding practices.

I worked on Codeigniter, Magento, HTML5, CSS3, Jquery, Javascript, AWS, eBay Web Services, Rakuten, UPS, USPS.

Delivered a multi-channel listing admin to sell products on various platforms like Amazon, eBay, Rakuten, Magento, etc.

I was responsible to handle a team of 12+ engineers included programmer, designer, testers, SEO professionals, Magento professionals, etc.

Implemented relational database to improve the speed of the product.

Implemented Tortoise SVN for version controlling and easy deployment to the servers.

Developed a REST-FUL / Micro-service API to interact with the Magento platform.

Evon Technologies
Senior Software Developer
March 2014 - September 2014 (7 months)
Dehra Dun Area, India

Developed & deliver a B2B & B2C portal in CakePHP by using Agile Methodologies.

I used OOPs, MYSQL (RDS), Javascript, Jquery, HTML5, CSS3 & Payment Gateway to deliver this project.

I was responsible for direct client interaction for all demos and on-going work via SKYPE and email.

Responsible for sprints/module deployment to servers.

As a Lead person of this project, I was responsible for the code and product quality as well.

Responsible for database designing as per requirements and application flow.

Assisted the colleagues to resolve their technical issues related to bugs, correct database structure, payment gateway integration, good coding practices, etc.

Softatek

Senior Software / PHP Web Developer September 2010 - January 2014 (3 years 5 months) Dehra Dun Area, India

Developed many applications by using many front-end and back-end technologies like PHP-5 (OOPS), MYSQL-5 (Relational Database), HTML, Javascript, Jquery, Bootstrap, CSS, Wordpress, Drupal, and YII framework.

Learned requirement gathering to plan work for good product and its delivery. Interacts with clients via skype and emails.

Code deployment from local machine to production.

Website optimization was a major responsibility in this company.

Worked on-site in Thailand to deliver a Hotel booking portal for the company.

Responsible to resolve the technical issues of other colleagues.

Daily reporting to BOSS directly.

I delivered many MLM Softwares, a stand-alone application (action-script 2.0), 2 hotel booking portals by using hotel APIs, many b2c and b2b websites.

I was a part of the student online classes portal which was developed in the YII framework.

Got experience in payment gateways (Paypal, Authorize.net) and third-party API implementation (Google Login, Google Map With Customization).

Worked on CMS like WordPress and Drupal for a very short period.

Education

Hemwati Nandan Bahuguna Garhwal University Bachelor of Science (BS), Science · (2007 - 2010)

CNI

Intermediate, Science · (2006 - 2007)

CNI Boys College

Intermediate · (2005 - 2007)